Dheeraj Pareek (1) Featured

Senior Software Engineer seeking roles in Software Development, Application Development, Project Management, Database Management, Release Management, Requirement Gathering, Troubleshooting, Programming, SQL Server, ASP. Net, SVN, SSIS, SSRS, T-SQL Programming



Current Designation: Senior Software Engineer Total Experience: 14 Year(s) 0 Month(s)

Current Company: Immediately Available Notice Period: 15 Days or less

Current Location: Gurgaon Highest Degree: MCA [Computers]

Pref. Location: Delhi / NCR, Gurgaon, Bengaluru / Bangalore Functional Area: IT Software - Application Programming /

Maintenance

Role: Software Developer

Industry: IT-Software/Software Services

Marital Status: Married

Key Skills: Senior Software Engineer, Software Developer, Software Development, Application Development, Project

Management, Database Management, Change Management, Release Management, Requirement

Gathering, Troubleshooting, Programming, SQL Server, JavaScript, ASP. Net, SVN

Verified: Email - id Phone Number |

Last Active: 22-Jan-21 Last Modified: 22-Jan-21

Summary

Having more than 13+ yrs. of experience in Microsoft Technology as a Sr. Software Engineer.

Having web-based application development experience (7 Year) in programming languages C#.Net, ASP.Net, MVC 4.0, WebAPI, Web Services, Windows Services, LINQ, Javascript. use this technology with backend MS-SQL 2008, MS-SQL 2014, SQLCE 3.5, Entity Framework, NHibernate.

Having professional software development experience (6+ Year) in the areas of (Microsoft Business Intelligence) Designing and Developing the SQL Server Integration Services-SSIS Packages and Hands on experience and outstanding knowledge in building and deploying the reports by using SQL Server Reporting Services-SSRS 2012.

Work Experience

Immediately Available as Senior Software Engineer Jul 2020 to Till Date

Austrax Technology India Pvt. Ltd as Senior Software Engineer Jul 2020 to Sep 2020

Worked as Sr. Software Engineer. Coding, Analysis, and Design are my basic responsibilities.

In Time Tech Vision Soft Pvt. Ltd. as Senior Software Engineer Jul 2010 to Jan 2020

Technology: SSIS, SSRS, Power BI, T-SQL programming (Sql Server 2000/2005/2008) Programming. C#, Asp.Net, ASP.NET MVC

Role:

Developed software solutions by studying information needs, conferring with users, studying systems flow, data usage, and work processes Worked on client side in Melbourne, Australia twice, for a period of 3 months Liaised with users for requirement gathering; prepared functional specifications and low-level design documents

Managed the maintenance of program modules including operational support,

problem resolution, production support, preventative and corrective

maintenance and enhancements

Assisted in determining operational feasibility through analysis, problem

definition, requirement analysis, and proposing solutions

contributed to code reviews

Tested modules developed by self & the team to ensure that these were as per desired quality standards;

managed client expectations as an indicator of quality

Coordinated with the client and cross-functional operations teams to identify and manage improvement activities

Client: IICE

Technology: SSIS, T-SQL programming

Project: IICE project is completely SSIS based project, which is used to populate the data warehouse, which are being used by several other applications. This project is already developed and being used in production environment. This project do not have proper error handling, so any error occurred in the project it is difficult to find the root cause of the issue and fix it. This project also have some logical data flow issues.

Implement error handling and log the logical data flow issue into custom tables for each packages. Email notification are implemented which is used to send email to respective users to troubleshoot the issue. Role / Responsibility

Understanding the flow of Individual SSIS packages and implement the error handling with logical dataflow.

2.

Client: HPDAAS

Technology: SSIS, SQL Server

Project: This project used to get the data for HP laptop, Monitor and accessory from different sources and import that information into existing data warehouse system. This project also takes data from business users in term of business excel files, which are loaded into database to filter the data, which should be display on the product web site.

This package also export the product information from data warehouse to particular SNS location where it is consumed by further application to display product information.

Role / Responsibility

Understand the client requirement and make changes in existing packages or create new packages accordingly.

Client: SAPL

Technology: SSRS, SSIS, T-Sql programming (Sql Server)

Project: Understand the requirement of SAPL plants work flow and design following reports.

Proactive vs. Reactive Work Orders report: The purpose of this report is to measure the effectiveness of maintenance planning and plant maintenance. It provides an indication of how much effort is being expended on preventing issues as opposed to reacting to issues.

Maintenance Schedule Compliance report: The purpose of this report is to measure how many scheduled work orders are completed as scheduled. The Simplot target is for ?95% of work orders to be completed as scheduled. If the figure is below this amount, this is a trigger for the Maintenance planner to investigate and identify issues that may be causing noncompliance.

Repairs And Maintenance Costs report: The purpose of this report is to track the actual costs spent on Repairs & Maintenance against budget. This allows the Maintenance Manager to ensure costs align with the budget commitment made and identify any issues with expenditure.

Role / Responsibility:

- Understanding the requirements of the customer.
- Develop Stored Procedures to enforce the business rules.
- Designed various types of reports with Complex Formulas, Custom Functions.

Key Solution as Senior Software Engineer

Aug 2009 to Jun 2010

1.

Client : PoweredPlans

: Asp.Net 3.5 ,C# , Sql Server 2005 Technology

: Poweredplan is an US based education system site. User can register on this site as individual Teacher, Project Group teacher (for school) and Student. Teacher can select his grade according his state. Admin provide lesson plan and plan material when teacher choose his grade level. Teacher can create class and student enrolls in these classes by teacher and self. Admin provide assignment for student and teacher can create own assignment (eight type of question) for student with audio and video effects. Teacher assigns assignment to student or class and student attempt these assignment, completing assignment by student than go for grading. Assignments have auto grading. There are three type of grading, Grading on assignment, Grading on Class and student complete grading. Other functionality is forum management, testimonial, Calendar, email system, Education store etc.

Role / Responsibility: Analysis, coding, design and bug fixing.

Delarue Cash Processing Systems as Software Engineer

Jul 2008 to Jul 2009

1.Client : Landsbanki Bank (Iceland)

: Sql Server 2005 (Stored procedures, Views programming for C# template) Technology

1/22/2021 https://freesearch.naukri.com/preview/printResume?uname=1397c5abfc74471211f15b381c47c4330c080c004c110d105112420a0c0...

: Landsbanki Interface -The main objectives of the Landsbanki interface are to improve the efficiency of the Project operating system at the cash centre and to remove the process of double entry of data that is currently causing delays. Currently, deposit details are entered into Maestro and then have to be re-keyed into the customer's AKLI accounts system. The proposed enhancements will enable the Maestro application to transfer the completed deposit transactions to a predefined location for import into the ALKLI accounting Interface as soon as they meet the relevant criteria. Role / Responsibility: Write stored procedure and views according business reports.

2

Client : Certis

: Sql Server 2005 (Stored procedures, Views programming for C# template) Technology

: Certis Same Day Credit Interface - The implementation of ISA at Certis requires an interface to insert ISA deposit data into the TempSDC table which is used by SDC process application used by Certis.A plug-in running on the existing ECM ISA Scheduler framework will be provided to extract data from the ISA database and insert records into the TempSDC table.

Role / Responsibility: Write stored procedures and views according to business reports.

Education

UG: B.Sc (Biology) from L.B.S College, Jaipur affiliated to University of Rajasthan in 2001

PG: MCA (Computers) from Maharishi Arvind Institute of Science and Management affiliated to University of Rajasthan in **2005**

IT Skills

Skill Name	Version	Last Used	Experience
SSIS, SSRS, Power BI, T-SQL			
C#, Asp.Net, ASP.NET MVC, Web Services			0 Year(s) 0 Month(s)
SQL Server 2000/2005			
Microsoft visual source safe 6.0			
SVN, GitHub			

Languages Known

Language	Proficiency	Read	Write	Speak
English	Proficient			
Hindi	Proficient			

Affirmative Action

Work Authorization

Category: General Job Type: Permanent

Physically Challenged: No Employment Status: Full time